midwich.com 2018-08-31

# Privacy Policy | Midwich

### Privacy Statement for Midwich Ltd Website

 **YOUR INFORMATION**

At Midwich, we take your privacy seriously.

We will only ever collect, keep, use or share your data where you have given us your consent, or if we are legally obliged to do so.

This privacy statement sets out how we comply with UK and European Union data protection requirements. This applies to the entire website. Any changes to these policies will be posted on this website.

You can also access this [**privacy statement via our homepage.**](https://www.midwich.com/about-us/privacy-policy/)

Midwich Limited and its subsidiaries are committed to respecting your privacy. We have structured our website so that, in general, you can visit Midwich Limited on the web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. Once you choose to provide us with any information by which you can be identified, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

For your protection, we are registered with the office of the Information Commissioner and have given all appropriate notifications.

 **WHAT WE COLLECT**

We may collect the following information:

  * Where you can order products, we will collect your name, contact and billing information, transaction and credit card information;
  * We require that users supply personal information, including name, company, telephone number, fax number and e-mail address prior to purchasing products and receiving any other company information or materials;
  * We may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experiences with our products, and contact preferences in order to provide you with further correspondence about our products and services;
  * Some pages use cookies, a data analysis technique.
  * When you attend one of our events, you may choose to provide us with your personal information (name, email address, mailing address) and let us know what you are interested in receiving further information from us. By doing so, you are giving us permission to enter your details into our systems on your behalf and share your details with our supplier partners who presented at the event you attended.

**HOW WE USE PERSONAL DATA**

We use this information to operate our business activities effectively, understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping; 
  * Improve our products and services; 
  * Customer care procedures; 
  * Provide information about new products, special offers or other relevant information you may find interesting; 
  * To offer you credit terms for the purchase of products or services from the site; 
  * Order fulfilment; and 
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by e-mail, phone, fax, or mail.

**WHO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION WITH AND YOUR CHOICES**

We may use your personal information for the purposes set out in this statement.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law.

When you provide any information on line, you should look for the boxes on the user details registration page. You can click to say that you do or do not want the information to be used by anyone for direct marketing purposes. You may change your mind at any time by writing to or e-mailing:

 _The Marketing Department, Midwich Limited, Vinces Road, Diss, Norfolk, IP22 4YT_

Email: [marketing@midwich.com](mailto:marketing@midwich.com) (please put ‘Unsubscribe’ in the subject line).  

 **WHAT IF YOU THINK WE HAVE INCORRECT INFORMATION OR YOU WOULD LIKE A COPY OF THE INFORMATION WE HOLD ABOUT YOU?**

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under previous and current data protection legislation (and in particular the General Data Protection Regulations (the GDPR). Requested information will be provided free of charge unless the volume of information justifies charging a reasonable fee (based on the administrative cost of supplying the requested data), or the request is a repeat request. Each of these types of cases will be considered individually.

If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to:

 _The Marketing Department, Midwich Limited, Vinces Road, Diss, Norfolk, IP22 4YT_

Email: [gdpr@midwich.com](mailto:gdpr@midwich.com) 

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write or e-mail us as soon as possible to the above address. We will correct any information which was found to be incorrect promptly.

 **SECURITY**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect on line. We use encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. 

We may transfer personal data to third countries or international organisations only if we are satisfied that the recipient has provided appropriate safeguards, and on condition that enforceable data subject rights and effective legal remedies for data subjects are available.

 **OTHER WEBSITES**

Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question. 

Those sites may not provide appropriate safeguards, or enforceable rights and effective legal remedies for you.

 **REMARKETING POLICY**

Midwich uses a Google remarketing cookie on our website – this allows us to collate lists of visitors who have visited our website, and show tailored, targeted adverts to them at a later date.

Our remarketing activities are limited to the Google Display Network – a network of websites and blogs throughout the Internet. Midwich may show adverts about our services to you if you have previously visited our website and are viewing a website that is part of the Google Display network.

Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Midwich website. Any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy.

You may opt out of the remarketing cookie by visiting your Google’s Ad Settings, usually reachable through the following link: **<http://www.google.com/settings/> **

 **HOW WE USE COOKIES**

A cookie is a piece of text which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, your browser adds that text in a small file. A cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. For example, when you visit an electronic store, a cookie makes it easier to shop, by allowing you to place things into a shopping basket; the basket itself is not the cookie, the cookie is placed on your hard drive and keeps track of your basket versus others in use at the same time. 

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. Denial of a traffic log cookie should not prevent you from using one of these sites. 

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. This practice is strictly in force. We know that people have concerns about cookies, but we believe that the benefit we both gain from their proper use is worthwhile. You may set your web to notify you of cookie placement requests or decline cookies completely. You can delete the files that contain cookies - those files are stored as part of your internet browser.

 _Policy Approved by:_  
 **Anthony Bailey (Group Finance Director)**
